Good Morning!
Let me see your Bible.
This one is as old as my age.
There are many latest, new versions and all that but this one is very new.
Hallelujah.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We all want to know more of our wonderful, unseen Guest.
Everyone wants to know.
You know you are walking but you know Someone is with you.
You know you are talking but Someone is there talking for you.
You know as you are sitting, Someone is sitting behind you, before you.
You just want to know more of your wonderful, unseen Guest.
Everyone wants to know.
If I'm alone here, I cannot stand here
because if I tell you what many hearts are saying, "Who is this man?
What does he want to do? Is that the one they are talking about?"
Let's see what he will do".
What do you want to see?
A lot of things are going on in your heart.
Many say, "Oh, what is going to happen? Well, let's see".
"I've been watching this man on Emmanuel TV and what does he want to say?"
If I were alone I would not be able to stand here today but Someone is with me.
Everyone of us wants to know more of our wonderful, unseen Guest.
If I'm talking to you?
If you sleep, you know Someone is sleeping with you; that is why you can see today.
You sleep, you wake up. If not Someone with you, you would not be able to wake up.
Tell you neighbour, "We all want to know more of our wonderful, unseen Guest".
That will take me to the title, 'Our Supernatural Guest'.
Let's quickly take a look at the book of John 14
and then we can take our reading from verse 15 there.
Jesus promised the Holy Spirit.
He promised the Holy Spirit.
He has promised He will never fail
I will follow Him
That is why you are following Him.
He has promised He will never fail
His faithfulness is forevermore
Think about that.
He has promised His faithfulness will never what?
- Never fail.
Here you are today, eating, sleeping, walking, looking freely because of His promise.
Let's take our reading from verse 15:
"If you love me, keep my commands.
And I will ask the Father..."
"I will ask the Father" - listen to that.
"...and He will give you another advocate" - helper.
In some of your Bibles, it says, comforter.
"He will give you another advocate to help you and be with you forever."
Not now alone - forever.
Take your time to read.
We will have a lot of texts in the book of Acts of Apostles.
Let me just give you a few you can take note of.
After the service today, take your time to read over this text.
This will also lead us to the books of Acts 4:23,
Acts 6:3,
Acts 13:52 - that will also be one of our proof readings,
Acts 4:31.
The one about you in person, in particular is Ephesians 5:18.
That will also lead us to that.
Acts 16:6-7.
Our Supernatural Guest
Unseen Guest
The yearning, we are yearning...
If I were alone, I would not be able to do all this. Someone is with me.
If I were alone, I would not be able to escape this tragedy. Someone is with me.
Tell your neighbour, "Someone is with me in the person of the Holy Ghost".
I can't hear you.
[Someone is with me in the person of the Holy Ghost.]
King of kings, Lord of lords I worship
In that text John 14:15-16, it says, "If you love me, keep my commands".
What does that mean to you?
He does nothing without His Word. He speaks to us through His Word, by His Spirit.
I will take it again. It says, "If you love me, keep my commands".
You say you love me, you are a child of God.
Keep my commands because I speak to you through my Word, by my Spirit.
In verse 16, it says, "I will ask the Father and He will give you another advocate to help you...".
This means, the Holy Spirit is another Comforter, another Helper.
Jesus Christ was the first Helper, first Comforter.
The Holy Spirit is another Helper - I mean Comforter.
In the absence of Jesus, the Holy Spirit was to be sent -
to take the place of Jesus Christ.
Worthy You are worthy
King of kings Lord of lords You are worthy
King of kings Lord of lords I worship You
He was, in a sense, to take the place of Jesus - the Holy Spirit.
The Holy Spirit is to be with us forever.
Forever oh Lord Your Word is settled
In Heaven it is settled
You mean, His Word is settled in your heart?
Heaven here in my heart?
Forever oh Lord Your Word is settled
In Heaven it is settled
The Holy Spirit is to be with us forever - through His Word, by His Spirit.
This is why the first text in verse 15 says, "If you love me, keep my commands".
His Word reflects His character.
I love the Man of Galilee
For He has done so very much for me
He has forgiven me all my sins
And sent the Holy Ghost to me
I love the Man of Galilee
If you love Him, say, "I love the Man of Galilee".
If you love Him, keep His Word.
He speaks to us through His Word by His Spirit because His Word reflects His character.
This is why the Bible says the Holy Spirit is not known or receved by everyone
but only those who keep His Word, only those who prepare for Him.
This is why many of you say, "What is Holy Spirit?" You don't know what Holy Spirit is.
You cannot receive the Holy Spirit without keeping His Word, abiding by His Word.
He said, "If you love Me, keep My Word".
The Apostles knew Jesus because they knew the Holy Ghost.
You know Jesus; you know the Holy Ghost.
To know Jesus is to know His Word; to love Him, keep His Word.
Jesus was not only the embodiment of the Heavenly Father but also of the Heavenly Spirit.
Note: First, He is a person. Second, He is divine.
A person has the ability to walk; the Holy Spirit walks as He wills.
In Acts 16:6-7, it says a person has the ability to decide.
"Okay."
"This one."
"Which?"
You have the ability to decide -
exercising the will through the mind; that is a person for you
but the Holy Spirit has the power of choice.
Okay, you have decided it but this is the right (one).
Absolutely!
Final - that is the Holy Spirit.
That is why people like me can be here today.
Each time you are trying to give me a wrong direction,
the Father in Heaven will say, "No, don't follow that direction; this is the direction".
Each time you are trying to give me a rumour, "Man of God, this is what has happened!",
I'm a good listener; I will listen to you.
By the time I have listened to you, you have said it...
Absolutely, the Holy Spirit is there to say, "No, what they are saying, it is not like that. This is the way".
He is Lord
He is Lord Amen
That is all!
He has risen from the dead
He is Lord
Every knee shall bow
Every tongue confess
That Jesus Christ is Lord
That is, that Jesus Christ is final.
A person has the ability to teach; He is the Ultimate Teacher!
In that book of John 14:26, the Holy Spirit teaches as He wills.
You can go out to witness, to testify, but He testifies, He witnesses.
Who are you?
That is the question, as a Christian.
The Bible says in that book of Ephesians 5:18, Who are you as a Christian?
"Do not get drunk on wine, which leads to debauchery.
Instead, be filled with the Spirit."
This means, all Christians should be filled with the Spirit.
What is the difference between being baptised in the Spirit and being filled with the Spirit?
That is the question you need to ask yourself.
If you take it to the book of Acts 13:52, Acts 4:31 and Acts 6:3.
Okay, let's take a look at Acts 4:31.
When they had prayed, the place was shaken and they were all filled with the Spirit.
In that Acts 13:52, it says, "And the disciples were filled with joy and with the Holy Spirit."
Back to 31.
It says, when they had prayed, the place was shaken and they were all filled with the Spirit
and spoke the Word of God boldly - with boldness.
Take note - without evidence of miraculous power.
That is a Christian - without evidence of miraculous power.
This means, we could now say,
all that are baptised in the Holy Spirit will be filled with the Holy Spirit
but all that are filled with the Holy Spirit may not be baptised in the Holy Spirit.
Take note of that.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When one is baptised in the Holy Spirit, he is also filled with the Holy Spirit.
But one may be filled with the Holy Spirit and not be baptised in the Holy Spirit
because the baptism of the Holy Spirit will not allow your spirit to be free.
He is in total control of your spirit, has dominion of your spirit.
Man's spirit would not be free, not allowed to do his will.
But to be filled by the Spirit - there is an option; it is an optional matter.
To be filled by the Spirit, as a Christian, is an optional matter.
But to be baptised in the Spirit is total submission.
A suggestion must be given to you from the Spirit.
In every step, in every moment, a suggestion must come from the Spirit -
when one is baptised in the Holy Spirit, under complete dominion of the Holy Ghost.
But in that book of Acts when the disciples were filled with joy and with the Holy Ghost,
without evidence of supernatural power.
So this is what the book of Ephesians 5:18 says there.
That all Christians must be filled by the Holy Ghost.
All Christians must be what?
[To be filled by the Holy Ghost.]
To be filled with the Holy Ghost is an optional matter - that is, leaves one with an option.
Will leave you with what? - An option.
It is a key area of the Scripture. I will take it one by one.
Because what is going on today, you can't imagine.
You don't know Christians; we don't know apostles; we don't know unbelievers again.
It is a level.
So people carry a dangerous mission today.
Once you become born again, you see people praying for people, for miracles,
praying for people for this, fasting or whatever.
The baptism of the Holy Ghost was Christ's baptism,
in the sense that no one else could administer it but Jesus alone.
No one - that is the baptism of the Holy Ghost.
It was wholly divine and human hands could not be used.
That is baptism of the Holy Ghost.
And all that are baptised in the Holy Ghost are filled with the Holy Ghost.
But not all that are filled with the Holy Ghost are baptised in the Holy Ghost.
I will try to demonstrate what I'm talking about.
It is like soaking a rug in water or oil
Leave it for a while.
When you now bring it out, you will see it dropping the oil.
The one that is dropping is the fullness.
To be filled with the Holy Ghost is the one dropping from this.
But the one that is soaked is that baptised one.
Baptism experience of the Holy Ghost will not leave man's spirit free.
In every step, in every moment, a suggestion must come from the Spirit.
"Go!" - suggestion must come from the Spirit to go.
But in the case of a Christian, you must be filled; there is an option.
Be filled with the Holy Ghost - this is what the Bible says. There is a difference.
Be filled with the Holy Ghost.
I have a Friend who never fails
Forevermore
Listen to that!
The Holy Ghost is to be with us forever; He is to support us forever -
another Comforter, another Helper.
Amen
Jesus never fails
Thank you. Did you listen to what Jesus said?
He said, "I will not leave you as an orphan".
But if you step aside, it gives the supernatural Guest a chance,
"Ok, take over. But I will be there".
What are you doing with your supernatural Guest?
Didn't you hear what the Bible says?
The Holy Spirit is not known, not received by everyone - only those who prepare for Him.
Are you?
You know Jesus; you know the Holy Spirit.
The Apostles knew Jesus; they knew the Holy Spirit.
Tell your neighbour, "You know Jesus; you know the Holy Spirit.
The Apostles knew Jesus; they knew the Holy Ghost.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Unknown
RV: Mel Flowers 09/09/2018